Guide to the Stanford University, Department of Physics, Lectures
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Deartment of Physics, lectures
1965-1980
SC0469
Stanford University. Department of Physics.
6 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer.
Information about Access
None.
Scope and Contents Note:
Summary: Lectures, with occassional exams and problem sets, from classes taught by Roberto D. Peccei, Sidney D. Drell, Harrison, Alexander L. Fetter, John D. Walecka, Peter Sturrock, Walter E. Meyerhof, Stuart Raby, Melvin Schwartz, Robert V. Wagoner, and others. Classes include quantum mechanics, electrodynamics, theory of fields, and plasma physics.
Access Terms
Drell, Sidney D., (Sidney David), 1926-; Fetter, Alexander L., 1937-; Harrison, Walter A., (Walter Ashley), 1930-; Meyerhof, Walter E. (Walter Ernst), 1922-; Peccei, Roberto.; Raby, Stuart.; Schwartz, Melvin, 1932-; Sturrock, Peter A. (Peter Andrew); Wagoner, Robert V.; Walecka, John Dirk, 1932-; Physics--Study and teaching.
Collection Contents
- Lectures from the following courses:
  - Classical Gravitation, Roberto D. Peccei, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Relativistic Quantum Theory, Sidney D. Drell, no date (Box 1)
  - The Physics of the Chemical Bond, Walter A. Harrison, 1977. (Box 1)
- Lectures from classes taught by Prof. Alexander L. Fetter:
  - Physics 29, Modern Physics, Spring 1980 (Box 2)
  - Physics 220, Classical Electrodynamics, Fall 1974 (Box 2)
  - Physics 221, Classical Theory of Fields, n.d. (missing page 1) (Box 2)
  - Physics 222, Classical Theory of Fields, Spring 1975 (Box 2)
  - Physics 270, Statistical Mechanics, Spring 1974, Spring 1977, and Spring, 1978 (Box 2)
- Lectures from class taught by Prof. Walter E. Meyerhof:
  - Physics 53, Electricity, Spring 1975 (Box 2)
- Lectures from classes taught by Prof. Roberto Peccei:
  - Physics 220, Classical Theory of Fields, Fall 1975 and Fall 1976 (Box 2)
  - Physics 221, Classical Theory of Fields, Winter 1977 (Box 2)
  - Physics 330, Advanced Quantum Mechanics, Spring 1976 (Box 2)
- Lectures from classes taught by Prof. Roberto Peccei:
  - Physics 330, Advanced Quantum Mechanics, Fall 1977 (Box 3)
  - Physics 331, Advanced Quantum Mechanics, Winter 1978 and Fall 1979 (Box 3)
  - Physics 332, Advanced Quantum Mechanics, Spring 1976 and Spring 1978 (Box 3)
- Lectures from class taught by Prof. Stuart Raby:
  - Physics 220, Classical Electrodynamics, Fall 1979 (Box 3)
- Lectures from class taught by Prof. Melvin Schwartz:
  - Physics 61, Advanced Freshman Physics, n.d. (Box 3)
- Lectures from classes taught by Prof. Peter Andrew Sturrock:
  - Applied Physics 103, Stellar and Galactic Astronomy, Winter 1976 (Box 4)
  - Applied Physics 320, Introduction to Plasma Physics I, Winter 1964 (Box 4)
  - Physics 321, Introduction to Plasma Physics II, Winter 1963 plus 1964 supplement, (2 copies, slightly different) (Box 4)
  - Engineering 206, Introduction to Plasma Physics III, Spring 1965 (Box 4)
  - Applied Physics 361/Engineering 208, Astrophysics II, Winter 1965/66 (Box 4)
  - Applied Physics 364, Radiation from Plasmas, Winter 1970 (Box 4)
- Lectures from class taught by Prof. Robert V. Wagoner:
  - Physics 15, Cosmic Evolution, Winter 1977 (Box 4)
- Lectures from classes taught by Prof. J.D. Walecka:
  - Physics 330, Advanced Quantum Mechanics, Autumn 1967/68 (Box 4)
  - Physics 331, Advanced Quantum Mechanics, Winter 1967/68 (Box 4)
  - Physics 332, Advanced Quantum Mechanics, Spring 1967/68 (Box 4)
  - Physics 342, Nuclear Theory III, Spring 1965 (Box 4)
  - Physics 371, Structure of Condensed Matter, Spring 1975 (Box 4)
- Article by Prof. J.D. Walecka:
  - Semi-Leptonic Weak Interactions in Nuclei, 1971 and 1978 versions (Box 4)
- Robert White:
  - Lectures on magnetism, Physics 200, Fall 1967 (Box 4)
- Stanley Wojcicki:
  - Problem sets for Physics 250, High Energy Physics, Winter 1978 (Box 4)
- Unspecified professor:
  - Physics 29, Modern Physics, Spring 1976 (Box 4)